Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman has given
a big gift to the insurance sector in today's budget,
which the insurance
sector was demanding. The FD limit has been
increased from 49 per cent to 74 per cent.
This will have two benefits for insurance companies.
Foreign companies will be
able to invest in Indian insurance companies.
Now Indian companies will be able to get new technology and
new capital, so that
customers will also get better products and
competition will increase. Along with this, regarding a
big culture of management and ownership
control, the Finance
Minister has also clarified that from independent
directors to
management directors in the board, up to 50% will be
Indian. There is an
amendment in this Insurance Act 1938, so it has been completely
balanced.
Foreign capital will also come to the companies. Insurance companies up to 74 per cent
are now high leveraged
here. Along with this, there were concerns related to job management and
ownership, the
Finance Minister has now removed that, so this is
very big news for insurance.
Now the FDI limit for the insurance sector has been
increased from 49 per cent to 74 per
cent.